Guide to the Joseph D. Cusick Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Joseph D. Cusick papers
1949-2006
SC0871
Cusick, Joseph D.
8.25 Linear feet
Collection primarily relates to his fundraising activities on behalf of Stanford University (as an alum and as a member of the Stanford Associates) and the reunions of the Class of 1951, held between 1976 and 2006. Included are correspondence, reports, manuals, newsletters, publications, clippings, programs, and a few photographs. There are also files pertaining to the Campus Conference (an Alumni Association event), 1960-66, and student disruptions on campus, 1969-73.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Joseph D. Cusick earned his AB at Stanford in 1951; he did post graduate work in law at the University of San Francisco and received his MBA from the University of Santa Clara. In addition to his career as an Air Force civilian executive, he has served in a number of fundraising campaigns for Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
Collection primarily relates to his fundraising activities on behalf of Stanford University (as an alum and as a member of the Stanford Associates) and the reunions of the Class of 1951, held between 1976 and 2006. Included are correspondence, reports, manuals, newsletters, publications, clippings, programs, and a few photographs. There are also files pertaining to the Campus Conference (an Alumni Association event), 1960-66, and student disruptions on campus, 1969-73.
Access Terms
Cusick, Joseph D.; Stanford Alumni Association; Stanford University. Stanford Associates.; College students--Political activity--California.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accesion ARCH-2007-099
  One oversized panorama photograph of the Class of 1951 at their 40th Reunion was removed and added to the Stanford Historical Photograph Collection under the number GP 16457.
  - Campus Conference 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campus Conference 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Campus Conference 1963 (Class Leaders' Workshop, Alumni Assembly) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campus Conference 1964 (Class Leaders' Workshop, Alumni Assembly) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Assembly 1965/Alumni Report (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campus Conference 1965 [includes photograph of Cusick] (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Campus Conference 1965 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Campus Conference 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wallace Sterling (includes 2 photographs), 1961-85 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pitzer Inauguration 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Troubles 1969-73" (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Troubles 1969-73" (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Troubles 1969-73" (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Troubles 1969-73" newsprint (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Alumni and fund raising – correspondence and other materials, 1970-71 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Volunteer Leadership Conference 1970, 1970; Annual Fund Report 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Volunteer Recognition Seminar 1970-71 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Assembly 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Robert L. Pierce and Alumni Association 1973-75 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Introduction of Prof. Herant Katchadourian at Alumni Assembly, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Association (includes Executive Director application) 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - University Seminar 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Fund, 1966 and earlier (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Fund, 1966 and earlier (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Class Fund 1966-67 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Class Fund 1966-67 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Fund 1967-68 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Fund 1967-68 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Class Fund 1968-69 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Class Fund 1968-69 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual Fund Conference 1967-68 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Campaign for Stanford (published booklet and Sterling letter) 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Class Fund II 1968-69 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Class Fund II 1968-69 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Annual Fund 1969-70 Working folder (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Annual Fund 1969-70 Working folder (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual Fund – Programs for Growth 1969-70 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Quad Report [published item] 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Annual Fund 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Annual Fund 1971-72, Quad Program Natl. Vice-Chairman (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Annual Fund 1971-72, Quad Program Natl. Vice-Chairman (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1967 Case Statement materials – "An Alumnus Looks at Annual Giving" (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Manuals, Briefs, Case Statements 1962-67 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annual Fund 1969 (AGPS) & Annual Fund Conference 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ad-Hoc Committee Annual Fund/Alumni Association 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Annual Fund Creative Committee 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Annual Fund Class Agent 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Parents Committee, letter of thanks 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - University Library Appeal, The Campaign for Stanford, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lyman, Richard, correspondence 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Annual Fund Leadership Conference 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Centennial Campaign (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Stanford Associates Where we come from, who we are & what we do" 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates report and correspondence 8/6/70-12/31/72 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Associates minutes, etc., 1/1/73-8/31/76 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates Report 1972-82 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates, Board of Governors, minutes and correspondence, 10/20/76-12/31/79 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Associates, Board of Governors, minutes and correspondence, 11/25/80-1/26/82 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Communications Committee, Stanford Associates, 1981-93 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Associates Readership Survey, report 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates miscellaneous correspondence, 1978-82 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Associates miscellaneous correspondence, survey, etc. 1981-82 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates Report (includes 2 photographs) 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates newsletter/ report, Communications Committee 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Associates Report summer 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Associates, Readership Survey and other business, 1980-81 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Communications Committee, miscellaneous 1977-81 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Communications Committee 1972-79 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Long Range Planning, Ad Hoc Committee for Publicity, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Associates miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-81 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates membership committee, 1971-76 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Associates membership committee, 1977-81 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates membership criteria, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gold Spike Award, 1976-78 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Gold Spike Award, 1979-2007 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Uncommon Man Award, Wallace Sterling and Fred Terman 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Drafts of "Stanford Associates Story" (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Associates story, source materials (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notes and responses to History of Stanford Associates (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nominating Committee, Stanford Associates, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates newsletter Aug. 1965-March 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates miscellaneous correspondence 1980s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University Fund Annual Report 1953-54 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Cardinal 1999-2000 (sports publication 2001) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Stanford 100 Years (centennial issue of the Alumni magazine) September 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Centennial information and memorabilia (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Centennial – newsprint (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Centennial – newsprint (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Centennial event in San Jose 1989 (includes photo of Cusicks) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cornerstone Weekend information 1987-88 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Reunions Class of 1951, 1956-71 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Reunions Class of 1951, 1956-71 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Reunions Class of 1951, newsprint, 1956-71 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Class of 1951 reunion newspapers, 1976-91, and other newsprint articles (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 25th Reunion, correspondence, programs, etc., 1976 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 25th Reunion, correspondence, programs, etc., 1976 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 30th Reunion, correspondence, planning, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 35th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc., 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 35th Reunion – newsprint (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Class of 1951, 40th Reunion correspondence, memorabilia, photo (includes Centennial materials), 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Centennial / 40th Reunion – newsprint 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Various articles related to Centennial and 40th Reunion of Class of 1951 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Various articles related to Centennial and 40th Reunion of Class of 1951 – newsprint (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 40th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc. (1 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 40th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc. (2 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 40th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc. (3 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 45th Reunion, correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc., (1 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 45th Reunion, correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc., (2 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 45th Reunion, correspondence, programs, memorabilia, etc., [includes photograph] (3 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Condoleezza Rice: Cusick's letters to her and his introduction of her at ASUL talk, 1996-98 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photos (in photocopy form only), articles, etc. for various reunions (includes "Stanford Alphabet Book" prepared for 40th Reunion by Kathy Moore Cusick and a booklet on Roble Hall, 1949) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Class book submission, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Class book – newsprint items (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Daily 104th Year Sunday June 16 [1996] (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - '51 Reunion Giving Action 1996-97 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - '51 45th Reunion fundraising (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - '51 Names/Reunion giving, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 50th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 50th Reunion correspondence, programs, memorabilia (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 50th reunion, newsprint articles, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Reunion thank-you's, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 50th Reunion fundraising campaign (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 50th Reunion campaign wrap-up 2002 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 50th Reunion programs, etc., 2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 50th Reunion Class Book (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 50th Reunion Class Book supplement (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 50th Reunion Campaign Report (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Class of 1951, 25th Reunion – images; 55th Reunion 500-picture slide show, 2006; 2 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 55th Reunion correspondence, programs, etc., 2006 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Hennessy correspondence, Dec. 2005-Jan. 2006 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Newsprint from Hennessy correspondence folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Special Gifts Campaign, 50th Reunion, correspondence, report, etc. (1 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Special Gifts Campaign, 50th Reunion, correspondence, report, etc. (2 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Special Gifts Campaign, 50th Reunion, correspondence, report, etc. (3 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Special Gifts Campaign, 50th Reunion, correspondence, report, etc. (4 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1974, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1979-80 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1982, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1986, 1988, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1992, 1994-95 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Associates directories, 1996-97, 1998-99 (Box 17, Folder 4)